Guide to the Alyse Gregory Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1898-1967; Series I; 23.05; (54 boxes)
  - GREGORY AND PINNEO FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Gregory, James G.
      - AG (Box 51, Folder 878-879)
      - Gregory, Jean L. Pinneo, 1917 Jan 14 (Box 51, Folder 880)
    - Gregory, Jean L. Pinneo
      Sometimes called "Nettie" or "Jennie"
      - AG (Box 51, Folder 881-894)
      - AG (Box 52, Folder 895-900)
      - AG (Box 52, Folder 901-908)
      - Byington, Joan, 1933 Dec 2 (Box 52, Folder 909)
      - Gregory, James G., 1905-[17] (Box 52, Folder 910-911)
      - Gregory, Ward, 1905, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 912)
      - Pinneo, Dotha Stone, 1905-17, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 913-915)
      - Pinneo, James Arthur, 1905 Jul 4 (Box 53, Folder 916)
        Sometimes called "Pinney"
      - White, Virginia A., n.d. (Box 53, Folder 917)
        Sometimes called "Mrs. G. W. White," "Nettie," or "Net Net"
      - Other correspondents, 1899, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 918)
      - Letters from Jean L. Pinneo Gregory to family members (transcripts), [189-?]-1937. n.d. (Box 53, Folder 919-925)
        Includes letters from James Arthur Pinneo to AG
    - Pinneo, Dotha Stone
      - AG (Box 53, Folder 926)
      - Limedorfer, Eugene, 1906 Sep 29 (Box 53, Folder 927)
    - Other family letters
      - Pinneo, James A. from AG, 1933-37 (Box 53, Folder 928-931)
        See also: Gregory, Jean L. Pinneo, Box 53, folders 919-925
      - White, Virginia A. from AG, 1928-41 (Box 53, Folder 932-933)
      - -----, [Ouida?] Alyse to AG, 1967 Aug 22 (Box 53, Folder 934)
      - ----- (uncle) to AG, 1898 Mar 28 (Box 53, Folder 935)
      - Letters from AG to family members (transcripts), 1911-40, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 936-941)
- Diaries, 1910-1967; Series II; 1.89; (5 boxes)
  - ORIGINAL DIARIES
    - Diary, 1925 Jul-26 Apr (Box 55, Folder 942)
      Entries preceded by notes concerning Paul Piel, Llewelyn Powys, and Scofield Thayer
    - Diary, 1930 Dec-33 Jul (Box 55, Folder 943-945)
    - Diary, 1933 Jul-36 Nov (Box 55, Folder 946-947)
    - Diary, 1936 Dec-39 Dec (Box 55, Folder 948)
    - Diary, 1939 Dec-40 Mar (Box 55, Folder 949)
    - Diary, 1940 Mar-Aug (Box 55, Folder 950)
    - Diary, 1940 Aug-41 Apr (Box 55, Folder 951)
    - Diary, 1941 May-Dec (Box 55, Folder 952)
    - Diary, 1941 Dec-42 Jul (Box 56, Folder 953)
    - Notes removed from diary, 1941 Dec-42 Jul (Box 56, Folder 954)
    - Diary, 1942 Jul-43 Jun (Box 56, Folder 955)
    - Notes removed from diary, 1942 Jul-43 Jun, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 956)
    - Diary, 1943 Jun-44 Sep (Box 56, Folder 957)
    - Diary, 1944 Sep-45 Oct (Box 56, Folder 958)
    - Diary, 1945 Oct-46 Jun (Box 56, Folder 959)
    - Notes removed from diary, 1945 Oct-46 Jun, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 960)
    - Diary, 1946 Jun-47 May (Box 56, Folder 961)
    - Diary, 1947 May-48 Mar (Box 56, Folder 962)
    - Diary, 1948 Mar-49 Oct (Box 57, Folder 963)
    - Diary, 1949 Oct-50 Dec (Box 57, Folder 964)
    - Notes removed from diary, 1949 Oct-50 Dec, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 965)
    - Diary, 1951 Jan-Dec (Box 57, Folder 966)
    - Diary, 1951 Dec-52 Apr (Box 57, Folder 967)
    - Notes removed from diary, 1951 Dec-52 Apr, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 968)
    - Notes, 1952, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 969)
      Includes addresses and other notes
    - Diary, 1952 Apr-53 Dec (Box 57, Folder 970)
    - Diary, 1954 Jan-Oct (Box 57, Folder 971)
    - Notes removed from diary, 1954 Jan-Oct, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 972)
    - Diary, 1954 Oct-57 Jan (Box 57, Folder 973)
    - Diary, 1957 Jan-64 Nov (Box 57, Folder 974)
    - Diary, 1964 Nov-67 Aug (Box 57, Folder 975)
    - Notes removed from diary, 1964 Nov-67 Aug, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 976)
  - TRANSCRIPTS
    - Excerpts, holograph, 1910 Dec-12 Apr (Box 58, Folder 977)
    - Excerpts, holograph, 1911 Nov-12 Jul (Box 58, Folder 978)
    - Excerpts, holograph, [1912?] Jul-Dec (Box 58, Folder 979)
    - Excerpts, holograph, 1912 Dec-13 Jul (Box 58, Folder 980)
    - Excerpts, holograph, 1914-15 (Box 58, Folder 981)
    - Excerpts, holograph, 1914 Jul-18 Sep (Box 58, Folder 982)
    - Excerpts, holograph, 1920-21 Dec (Box 58, Folder 983)
    - Excerpts, typescript, 1923 Jul-39 Dec (Box 58, Folder 984-989)
    - Excerpts, typescript, 1939 Dec-43 Jun (Box 58, Folder 990-993)
    - Excerpts, typescript, 1943 Jun-47 Mar (Box 58, Folder 994-996)
    - Excerpts, typescript, 1947 Mar-50 Feb (Box 59, Folder 997-998)
    - Excerpts, typescript, 1950 Feb-54 Jan (Box 59, Folder 999-1000)
    - Excerpts, typescript, 1954 Jan-60 Jan (Box 59, Folder 1001-1002)
    - Notes, holograph, 1955-64 (Box 59, Folder 1003)
- Writings, 1922-1948; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  - BOOKS
    - The Day is Gone (fragments), typescript, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1004)
      Other notes on versos
    - The Day is Gone (reviews), 1948, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1005)
    - Hester Craddock (reviews), 1931 Nov, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1006)
    - King Log and Lady Lea (reviews), 1929 Aug-Sep (Box 60, Folder 1007)
    - Novel (draft fragments), typescript, corrected, 1943 (Box 60, Folder 1008)
    - Randolph Bourne: Life and Selected Letters (draft), typescript, corrected (Box 60, Folder 1009-1011)
    - Wheels on Gravel (reviews), 1938-39, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1012)
  - SHORT STORIES
    - "The Golden Key," clipping from Cornhill Magazine, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1013)
    - "A Trust Betrayed," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1014)
  - ESSAYS
    - "Alice James" (draft), typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1015)
    - Anti-vivisection essay (fragment), clipping and photocopy from The Freethinker, with revisions, 1941 Sep 14 (Box 60, Folder 1016)
    - "Composte [sic] for Jottings or Skip and Snooze" (draft), holograph (Box 60, Folder 1017)
      About Louis Wilkinson
    - "The Ever Memorable John Hales," clipping from The Freeman, 1923 Jan 3 (Box 60, Folder 1018)
    - "A Feminine Jean-Christophe," clipping from The Freeman, with revisions, 1923 Mar 14 (Box 60, Folder 1019)
    - "A Friend of Flaubert," clipping from The Freeman, 2 copies, with revisions, 1923 Aug 1 (Box 60, Folder 1020)
      About Louise Colet
    - "The Function of the Critic" clipping from The Windmill (Box 60, Folder 1021)
    - "The Function of the Critic" (review), 1944 Dec 2 (Box 60, Folder 1022)
    - "Laughter, Wit and Humor," clipping from The Freethinker, with revisions, 1943 Oct 3 (Box 60, Folder 1023)
    - "The Limitations of the English Mind," clipping from The Adelphi (Box 60, Folder 1024)
    - "Nelson and Lady Hamilton," clipping from The Outline: Supplement to John O'London's Weekly, 1933 Aug 19 (Box 60, Folder 1025)
    - "Notes on C. E. P. P." (notes and draft), holograph and typescript (Box 60, Folder 1026)
      About Philippa Powys; notebook also include household notes
    - "Poets and the BBC," clipping from The Freethinker, 1943 Oct 31 (Box 60, Folder 1027)
    - "The Problem of Mr. Sitwell," clipping from The Freeman, 2 copies, with revisions, 1923 Aug 22 (Box 60, Folder 1028)
    - "Reflections of an Expatriate," (drafts), holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 60, Folder 1029)
    - [Samuel Taylor Coleridge] (draft fragment), typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1030)
    - "Sherwood Anderson," clipping (Box 60, Folder 1031)
    - "Tribute to a Poet" (drafts), typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1032)
      About John Redwod Anderson
    - "Women and Age," (drafts), holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 60, Folder 1033)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - Book reviews, clippings, 1922-48, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1034-1036)
      Most from The Dial
    - Letters to editors, 1944, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1037)
    - Notes and fragments concerning LP correspondence (Box 60, Folder 1038)
    - Notes and fragments concerning LP and John Cowper Powys (Box 60, Folder 1039)
    - Other notes and fragments (Box 60, Folder 1040)
- Notebooks, 1940-1967; Series IV; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  See also: Series III. Writings, "Notes on C. E. P. P.," Box 60, folder 1026.
  - "1. Arthur Waley: The Way and Its Power. 2. Milton" (Box 61, Folder 1041)
  - "Bertrand Russell: History of Western Philosophy" (4 volumes) (Box 61, Folder 1042-1043)
  - "Kafka. Santayana: Realm of Essence", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1044)
  - Notes removed from "Kafka. Santayana: Realm of Essence", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1045)
  - "La Rochefoucauld. IV. Marquis de La Fare. L'abbé Arnauld", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1046)
  - "Literature. General" (2 volumes), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1047-1048)
  - Notes removed from "Literature. General", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1049)
  - "Santayana, etc.", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1050)
  - Notes removed from "Santyana, etc.", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1051)
  - "Shakespeare", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1052)
  - Notes removed from "Shakespeare", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1053)
  - "Whitehead: The Function of Reason", 1965 (Box 61, Folder 1054)
  - Untitled notebook, 1940, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1055)
  - Untitled notebook, 1950, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1056)
  - Notes removed from untitled notebook, 1950, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1057)
  - Untitled notebook, 1952, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1058)
  - Untitled notebook, 1957, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1059)
  - Notes removed from untitled notebook, 1957, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1060)
  - Untitled notebook, 1961-62, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1061)
  - Notes removed from untitled notebook, 1961-61, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1062)
  - Untitled notebook, 1966-67 (Box 62, Folder 1063)
  - Untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1064)
  - Notes removed from untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1065)
  - Other untitled notebooks, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1066-1069)
- Photographs, 1905-1967; Series V; 2.25; (4 boxes)
  - ALBUMS
    - Album of travels in Europe, [ca. 1905] (Box 63, Folder 1070)
    - Album of cruise to Indonesia, [ca. 1920?] (Box 64, Folder 1071)
  - PEOPLE
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1946 Jun, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1072)
    - Ackland, Valentine (Box 65, Folder 1073)
    - Anderson, Gwyneth
      See: Anderson, John Redwood, Box 65, folder 1074
    - Anderson, John Redwood (and Gwyneth Anderson), 1959-66, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1074)
    - Costigan, Amne and Giovanni, 1960-63 (Box 65, Folder 1075)
    - Curry, Madeleine Walker (and her children) (Box 65, Folder 1076)
    - Gooden, Mona, 1952, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1077)
    - Gooden, Stephen, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1078)
    - Gregory, Alyse, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1079)
      See also: Moore, Marianne, Box 65, folder 1085
    - Gregory, Jean L. Pinneo, carte-de-visite, signed, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1080)
    - Hayman, Laure, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1081)
    - Lindsay, Derek (Box 65, Folder 1082)
    - Metcalf, Addison
      See: Metcalf, Henriette, Box 65, folder 1083
    - Metcalf, Henriette (and family), 1959, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1083)
    - Miller, Walter ("E. Chaldon"), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1084)
    - Moore, Marianne and AG, made by Doris Ulmann (Box 65, Folder 1085)
    - Nordlinger, Marie, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1086)
    - Powys, Charles (wedding), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1087)
      Includes photographs of William, Elizabeth, and Gilfrid Powys; Tony and Rose Dyer; and others
    - Powys, John Cowper and "Reginald" (Box 65, Folder 1088)
      Notes on verso written by Phyllis Playter
    - Powys, Llewelyn (and unidentified children) (Box 65, Folder 1089)
    - Rose, Rosamond (Box 65, Folder 1090)
    - Smith, Mrs. [Harry?] ("West Chaldon"), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1091)
    - Watson, James Sibley, Jr. (and family), 1958 Dec-66 Jun (Box 65, Folder 1092-1103)
    - Watson, James Sibley, Jr. (and family), 1966-67, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1104-1112)
    - -----, George and [Ailda?] (wedding) (Box 66, Folder 1113)
    - -----, Margaret, "Juanita," and a boat (relating to John Fisher), [1957?], n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1114)
    - Unidentified (Switzerland?) (Box 66, Folder 1115)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1116)
  - PLACES
    - "Door end of study," in unidentified house, captioned by LP (Box 66, Folder 1117)
    - Velthams Cottage, Morebath, Tiverton, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1118)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1119)
  - PHOTOGRAPH ENVELOPES
    - Envelope (England) (Box 66, Folder 1120)
    - Envelope (Switzerland) (Box 66, Folder 1121)
- Artworks, 1891-1959; Series VI; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Blanche, Jacques Émile. Drawing of Marcel Proust (photograph reproduction), 1891 Oct 1 (Box 67, Folder 1122)
  - Fisher, John. Diagram of a boat, pencil; and drawings of animals, pen and ink (Box 67, Folder 1123)
  - Fisher, William. "Patchin Place, Greenwich Village," painting (printed reproduction), n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1124)
  - Gibbings, Robert. Engravings, signed, 1933, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1125)
    Includes an engraving inscribed to LP
  - Gooden, Stephen. Engravings, signed, 1927-47 (Box 67, Folder 1126)
    Inscribed by Stephen and Mona Gooden to AG
  - Madrazo y Kuntz, Federico de. Drawing of Marie Mordlinger (printed reproduction, 2 copies), n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1127)
    One copy inscribed by Nordlinger to AG
  - Schjelderup, Gerik. Drawing of John Redwood Anderson (reproduction), 1959 Mar 1 (Box 67, Folder 1128)
    Inscribed to AG
  - Unidentified. Drawing Joan Wilkinson (reproduction), n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1129)
  - Unidentified. Painting of Joan Wilkinson (reproduction), n.d. (Box 67, Folder 1130)
- Clippings and Other Printed Material, 1923-1967; Series VII; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1950-59, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1131)
  - Agostin, Tibor, 1961 (Box 68, Folder 1132)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1961 Apr 6 (Box 68, Folder 1133)
  - Chydyok and East Chaldon (Box 68, Folder 1134)
  - Collins, Vere H. (Vere Henry), n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1135)
  - Costigan, Giovanni and Costigan, Amne, 1951-61, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1136)
  - The Dial, 1925-1929 (Box 68, Folder 1137)
  - Du Cann, C. G. L. (Charles Garfield Lott), 1940-42, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1138-1139)
  - Gregory, Alyse, 1924, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1140)
    Clippings regarding her marriage
  - Gregory family, 1931-61?, n.d (Box 68, Folder 1141)
  - Holloway, Mark, 1949 Aug 20 (Box 68, Folder 1142)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1952-57, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1143)
  - Nordlinger, Marie, 1942-61, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1144)
  - Patchin Place, 1953 Dec 6 (Box 68, Folder 1145)
  - Potocki de Montalk, Geoffrey, Count, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1146)
  - Powys, John Cowper, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1147)
  - Powys, Llewelyn, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1148)
    See also: Gregory, Alyse, Box 68, folder 1140
  - The Powys Bookshop, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1149)
  - Rose, Rosamond (Box 68, Folder 1150)
  - Santayana, George, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1151)
  - Smith, Stevie, 1965, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1152)
  - Thayer, Scofield, 1925-27, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1153)
  - Watson, Hildegarde, 1961 Dec 16 (Box 68, Folder 1154)
  - Woolsey, Gamel, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1155)
  - Other clippings and printed material, 1923-67, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1156)
- Other Papers, 1888-1967; Series VIII; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Address books, 1939, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1157-1158)
    See also: Series II. Diaries, Notes, Box 57, folder 969
  - Addresses and notes (Box 69, Folder 1159)
  - Lists of LP manuscripts, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1160)
  - Lock of LP's hair, 1888 (Box 69, Folder 1161)
  - Locks of LP's hair, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1162-1163)
  - Merrick, Frank. "J. R. A.," essay about John Redwood Anderson, typescript, carbon, with corrections (Box 69, Folder 1164)
  - Note concerning AG's death, [1967] (Box 69, Folder 1165)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence, Stoner, Oliver, Box 38, folders 656-659
  - Notes and documents concerning LP's death, 1939-40 (Box 69, Folder 1166)
  - Notes concerning the Gregory and Pinneo families (Box 69, Folder 1167)
  - Scrapbook made by Annetta Mullins, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1168)
  - Scrapbook made by Annetta Mullins (clippings removed), 1946-47, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1169)
- Papers of Others Held by Alyse Gregory, 1897-1950; Series IX; 2.1; (5 boxes)
  - LLEWELYN POWYS PAPERS
    - Correspondence
      - Abrahams, Mr. (transcript), 1935 Mar 30 (Box 70, Folder 1170)
      - Ackland, Valentine (transcripts), 1934-39, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1171)
      - Balfour, Henry (transcripts), 1935 Mar 9 (Box 70, Folder 1172)
      - Boissevain, Eugen, 1931-[34?] (Box 70, Folder 1173)
      - Boissevain, Eugen (transcripts), 1931-[34?] (Box 70, Folder 1174)
      - Brenan, Gerald, 1932-34, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1175-1178)
      - Brooks, Eleanor (transcripts), 1928 Mar (Box 70, Folder 1179)
      - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1920-39, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1180)
      - Brooks, Van Wyck, (transcripts), 1921-39 (Box 70, Folder 1181)
      - Byington, Jean L. Gregory, 1925-37, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1182)
      - Byington, Jean L. Gregory (transcripts), 1927-37, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1183)
      - Caesar, Julius (transcripts), 1935-36, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1184)
      - Cobb, James (transcripts), 1938 Dec 16 (Box 70, Folder 1185)
      - Cobb, Mrs. (transcript), 1936 May 12 (Box 70, Folder 1186)
      - Cole, Galbraith, 1923 Jun-Aug (Box 70, Folder 1187)
      - Cole, Galbraith (transcripts), 1923 Aug 6 (Box 70, Folder 1188)
      - Curry, Madeleine Walker (transcripts), 1938 Dec 26 (Box 70, Folder 1189)
      - Davies, Brynmor (transcripts), 1938 Mar 27 (Box 70, Folder 1190)
      - De Casseres, Benjamin (transcripts), 1936-39 (Box 70, Folder 1191)
      - de Lima, Agnes (transcripts), 1939 Nov 5 (Box 70, Folder 1192)
      - de Lima, Sigrid (transcripts), 1939 Sep-Oct (Box 70, Folder 1193)
      - Dreiser, Theodore (transcript), 1933 Jul 13 (Box 70, Folder 1194)
      - Du Maurier, Angela (transcript), 1939, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1195)
      - English, Herbert (transcripts), 1935 May 1 (Box 70, Folder 1196)
      - Ficke, Arthur Davison (transcript), 1927-36 (Box 70, Folder 1197)
      - Gibbings, Robert (transcripts), 1935, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1198)
      - Gooden, Mona (transcripts), 1937 Aug-Sep (Box 70, Folder 1199)
      - Gregory, Jean L. Pinneo, 1925-35, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1200)
      - Gregory, Jean L. Pinneo (transcripts), 1930-35?, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1201)
      - Griffiths, Glyn (transcripts), 1936-37 (Box 70, Folder 1202)
      - Hamish Hamilton Ltd., 1935 Feb 11 (Box 70, Folder 1203)
      - Hanson, Dorothy (transcript), 1938 Jul 16 (Box 70, Folder 1204)
      - Henderson, Hilary (transcripts), 1929, 1932 (Box 70, Folder 1205)
      - Holahan, Anne, n.y. Sep 17 (Box 70, Folder 1206)
      - Howe, P. P. (transcript), 1938 Feb 25 (Box 70, Folder 1207)
      - Jansen, Roy (transcripts), 1931 (Box 70, Folder 1208)
      - Johnson, Arthur (transcripts), 1926 Sep 2 (Box 70, Folder 1209)
      - Lewin, G. Harry (transcripts), 1934 (Box 70, Folder 1210)
      - Machen, Janet (transcripts), 1937, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1211)
      - Mannin, Ethel (transcripts), 1939 (Box 70, Folder 1212)
      - Marlow, Louis
        See: Wilkinson, Louis, Box 72, folder 1286
      - Marsh, Reginald (transcripts), 1929-39 (Box 70, Folder 1213)
      - Massingham, H. J. (Harold John) (transcripts), 1936, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1214)
      - Mead, Hazel (transcripts), 1926, 1938 (Box 70, Folder 1215)
      - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1932-[34] (Box 70, Folder 1216)
      - Millay, Edna St. Vincent (transcripts), 1932 Nov 26 (Box 70, Folder 1217)
      - Mitchison, Naomi (transcript), 1930 Jan 23 (Box 71, Folder 1218)
      - Moore, Marianne, 1923-27 (Box 71, Folder 1219)
      - Moore, Marianne (transcripts), 1926, 1928 (Box 71, Folder 1220)
      - Moule, A. C. (Arthur Christopher) (transcripts), 1939 Feb-Sep (Box 71, Folder 1221)
      - Mumford, Lewis, 1932 Aug 18 (Box 71, Folder 1222)
      - Munday, G. P. (transcripts), 1935 (Box 71, Folder 1223)
      - Musgrave, Clifford (transcripts), 1931-39 (Box 71, Folder 1224)
      - Musgrave, Margaret (transcript), 1937 Apr 18 (Box 71, Folder 1225)
      - Nisbet, Diana (transcripts), 1939 (Box 71, Folder 1226)
      - Oakeshott, Michael Joseph (transcripts), 1933, 1939 (Box 71, Folder 1227)
      - O'Neill, Bernard Price (transcripts), after Aug 1933 (Box 71, Folder 1228)
      - Penny, Lucy Powys (transcripts), 1918-33 (Box 71, Folder 1229)
      - Playter, Phyllis, 1925-27, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1230)
      - Playter, Phyllis (transcripts), 1929-37, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1231)
      - Pollock, H. Rivers (transcripts), 1924-36 (Box 71, Folder 1232-1233)
      - Powys, A. R. (Albert Reginald, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1234)
      - Powys, A. R. (Albert Reginald) (transcripts), 1910-35, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1235)
      - Powys, Faith (transcript), 1937 Mar 4 (Box 71, Folder 1236)
      - Powys, Gertrude M. (Gertrude Mary), 1931, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1237)
      - Powys, Gertrude M. (Gertrude Mary) (transcripts), 1916-33 (Box 71, Folder 1238)
      - Powys, John Cowper, 1907-39, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1239-1242)
      - Powys, John Cowper (transcripts), 1907-38, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1243-1247)
      - Powys, Katie
        See: Powys, Philippa, Box 72, folder 1256-1258
      - Powys, Littleton (transcripts), 1899-1939, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1248-1251)
      - Powys, Littleton Alfred, 1925 Oct-Nov (Box 72, Folder 1252)
      - Powys, Marian, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1253)
      - Powys, Marian (transcripts), 1908 Mar (Box 72, Folder 1254)
      - Powys, Mary Cowper (transcripts), 1897-1911 (Box 72, Folder 1255)
      - Powys, Philippa, 1925-36, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1256-1258)
      - Powys, Philippa (transcripts), 1915-38, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1259)
      - Powys, Theodore Francis (transcript), 1916 Apr 23 (Box 72, Folder 1260)
      - Powys, William, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1261)
      - Powys, William (transcripts), 1935-37 (Box 72, Folder 1262)
      - Randerson, Horace E. (transcripts), 1936 Jul (Box 72, Folder 1263)
      - Rose, Rosamond, 1937-39 (Box 72, Folder 1264)
      - Santayana, George, 1935-38 (Box 72, Folder 1265)
      - Santayana, George (transcripts), 1935-38 (Box 72, Folder 1266)
      - Scott-Maxwell, Denis (transcript), n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1267)
      - Scott-Maxwell, Florida, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1268)
      - Scott-Maxwell, Hilary
        See: Henderson, Hilary, Box 70, folder 1205
      - Sergeant, Elizabeth Shepley (transcript), 1926 Jul (Box 72, Folder 1269)
      - Siberell, Lloyd Emerson (transcripts), 1938 Oct 31 (Box 72, Folder 1270)
      - Srinivasa Iyengar, K.R. (transcripts), 1933-34 (Box 72, Folder 1271)
      - Symonds, Tom (transcript), 1928 Dec 14 (Box 72, Folder 1272)
      - Taylor, Bernard (transcript), after 1934 Sep (Box 72, Folder 1273)
      - Taylor, Hermione (transcript), 1939 (Box 72, Folder 1274)
      - Thayer, Scofield, 1926 Feb-Mar (Box 72, Folder 1275)
      - Townsend, Myron (transcripts), 1939 Aug-Oct (Box 72, Folder 1276)
      - Trask Harold (transcript), n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1277)
      - Van Doren, Irita Taylor (transcript), 1929 (Box 72, Folder 1278)
      - W. W. Norton & Company, 1937 May 5 (Box 72, Folder 1279)
      - Walker, Madeleine
        See: Curry, Madeleine Walker, box 70, folder 1189
      - Wallis, John (transcripts), 1933-39 (Box 72, Folder 1280)
      - Ward, Lynd (transcripts), 1933 (Box 72, Folder 1281)
      - Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1938 Dec 22 (Box 72, Folder 1282)
      - Warner, Sylvia Townsend (transcripts), 1935 Nov (Box 72, Folder 1283)
      - White, Mrs. G. W. (transcript), 1934 Aug 28 (Box 72, Folder 1284)
      - Wilkinson, Ann Reid (transcripts), 1927 Jan 11 (Box 72, Folder 1285)
      - Wilkinson, Louis (transcripts), 1928-39 (Box 72, Folder 1286)
      - Wood, Herbert George (transcripts), 1930 May 22 (Box 72, Folder 1287)
      - Woolsey, Gamel, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1288)
      - Wordsworth, Helen (transcript), 1938 May? (Box 72, Folder 1289)
      - Worvill, Roy Bernard (transcripts), 1938-39 (Box 72, Folder 1290)
      - Unidentified, 1927-39, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1291)
      - Unidentified (transcripts), 1936-39 (Box 72, Folder 1292)
    - Diaries
      - Original Diaries
        - "Diary of Travels in Palestine", [1928-29] (Box 72, Folder 1293)